Welcome. In the last lecture, we successfully set up an input through the new enhanced input
欢迎。在上一讲中，我们成功地通过新的增强型输入法设置了一个输入。
system. And in this lecture, let's look at how we can actually implement the climbing
系统。在这一讲中，让我们来看看我们如何才能真正实现我们想要的爬坡
system we want. By default, our character class already has many different movement
系统。在默认情况下，我们的角色类已经有许多不同的运动
modes. So we have a mode for walking, we have a mode for falling, for swimming. I like to
模式。所以我们有一个行走的模式，我们有一个跌倒的模式，有一个游泳的模式。我喜欢
have one of these when we're climbing. And in order to do this, we'll need to extend
我喜欢在攀爬的时候有一个这样的模式。为了做到这一点，我们将需要扩展
this custom movement mode. And we'll need to do it through our custom character movement
这个自定义运动模式。我们将需要通过我们的自定义角色运动
component. Go back to my project. If you go inside of this third person folder and inside
组件。回到我的项目中去。如果你进入这个第三人称文件夹，在蓝图里面
the blueprints, double click to open this BP_ThirdPersonCharacter. Open for Blueprint Editor. You can see by default,
蓝图，双击来打开BP_ThirdPersonCharacter。为蓝图编辑器打开。你可以看到，在默认情况下、
our character class already has a character movement component. And we'll need to override
我们的角色类已经有一个角色运动组件。而我们需要在代码中覆盖
this from code so that our character class can use the movement component that we are
以便我们的角色类可以使用我们将要创建的运动组件。
about to create. So I'm going to close this window and I'm going to go inside of this
即将创建的运动组件。所以我将关闭这个窗口，并进入这个
C++ classes folder. Inside of climbing system, Ramos button click to create a new class and
C++类文件夹。在攀登系统中，点击Ramos按钮，创建一个新的类，并选择所有的类。
select all classes. I'm going to type in character movement. So we're going to use this as the
选择所有的类。我将输入角色运动。所以我们将使用这个作为
parent class. Alright, after selecting it, I'm going to click next. Then I'm going to
父类。好的，选择之后，我将点击下一步。然后我将
rename this one to custom movement component. Then I'm going to click this public. I'm going
把这个重命名为自定义运动组件。然后我将点击这个公共的。我将
to use the public pervert for this structure in here. And I'm going to put it inside of
在这里为这个结构使用公共变态。我将把它放在
its own folder. I'm going to name this folder to components. Then I'm going to click create
它自己的文件夹。我将把这个文件夹命名为组件。然后我将点击创建
class. Alright, live coding succeeded. I'm going to compile from Visual Studio. I'm going
类。好了，现场编码成功了。我将从Visual Studio编译。我将
to close my project and click this reload all. Later, this custom movement component class
关闭我的项目，然后点击这个重新加载所有。以后，这个自定义运动组件类
is going to handle all the heavy lifting for our climbing. We're going to come back to
将为我们的攀登处理所有的重活。我们将返回到
it very soon. For now, we need to set up a way for our character to use this movement
它很快就会出现。现在，我们需要为我们的角色设置一种方法来使用这个运动
component class. And there's something that we need to do inside of the constructor of
组件类。我们需要在角色类的构造函数中做一些事情。
the character class. So I'm going to go to its header file. And for the constructor here,
角色类的构造函数中做一些事情。所以我将进入它的头文件。对于这里的构造函数、
I'm going to fill in a parameter. So it's going to be a const F object initializer. It's going
我将填入一个参数。所以它将是一个 const F 对象的初始化器。它将会是
to be a reference. I'm just going to call it object initializer. I'm going to fill out
是一个引用。我只是打算把它叫做对象初始化器。我将填写
this parameter to the CPP file. And to override the default movement component, we'll first
这个参数到CPP文件中。为了覆盖默认的运动组件，我们首先要
need to include the header file of our custom movement component. So go back to its CPP
需要包括我们自定义运动组件的头文件。所以请回到它的CPP
file. I'm going to copy this line and go back to my character class. You can see in here
文件。我将复制这一行，然后回到我的角色类。你可以看到在这里
by default, we already included this character movement component. Since we have a custom
默认情况下，我们已经包含了这个角色运动组件。由于我们有一个自定义的
one now, we don't need this anymore. So I'm going to paste that line in here. Then inside
我们就不再需要这个了。所以我要把这一行粘贴到这里。然后在
of this constructor, I'm going to start a new line. It's going to be super and followed
的构造函数中，我将开始一个新的行。它将会是super，后面是
by a parentheses. So it'll be object initializer. And this function inside of it that we can
后面加一个括号。所以它将是对象初始化器。它里面的这个函数，我们可以
use is called set default sub object class. So this is a template function. We'll need
被称为设置默认子对象类。所以这是一个模板函数。我们需要
to first fill in the class type, then you'll be the sub object name. So the class type,
首先填入类的类型，然后是子对象的名称。所以类的类型、
it will be our custom movement component. So I'm going to copy this and paste it in here.
它将是我们的自定义运动组件。所以我要复制这个并把它粘贴到这里。
Don't forget to add you in front of it. And the name here, in order for this to work,
不要忘记在前面加上 "你"。而这里的名字，为了让它发挥作用、
we'll need to use a static variable from the character class. So it's going to be a character
我们需要使用一个来自角色类的静态变量。所以它将是一个字符
double colon. And the variable is called character movement component name. You can see here
双冒号。而这个变量被称为字符运动组件名称。你可以看到这里
it says use this name if you want to use a different class for this character movement
它说如果你想为这个角色运动组件使用一个不同的类，就使用这个名字。
component. So this is the one that I'm going to use. All right, that's pretty much it.
组件。所以这就是我要使用的那个。好了，差不多就这些了。
I'm going to press control plus B to compile. All right, I have a successful compile and
我将按控制键加B来编译。好的，我已经成功地编译了，并且
same as other components, I like to hold the reference of this custom movement component
和其他组件一样，我想把这个自定义运动组件的引用放在
inside of our character class. So I'm going to go back to the header file. First thing,
在我们的角色类中。所以我要回到头文件中去。第一件事、
I'm going to forward declare the type. So I'm going to copy this custom movement component
我要向前声明这个类型。所以我将复制这个自定义运动组件
and I'm going to put it in here. Then I'm going to declare a variable under this follow
并把它放在这里。然后我将在这个下面声明一个变量
camera. So I'm going to copy its you property and paste it in here. So the class type will
相机。所以我要复制它的你属性并把它粘贴到这里。所以类的类型将
be this. And the name, I'm going to name it custom movement component. And I'm going to
是这个。而名字，我将把它命名为自定义运动组件。而且我将
change its category to movement. And now we need to find a way to actually assign values
把它的类别改为运动。现在我们需要找到一种方法来实际分配数值
to this pointer. And there's something we can do inside of the constructor. So go back
给这个指针赋值。我们可以在构造函数中做一些事情。所以请回到
to my CPP file. Right above we access this character movement. I'm going to assign a
到我的CPP文件。就在我们访问这个字符运动的上面。我将给我们刚刚创建的指针分配一个
valid value to the pointer that we just created. So it'll be custom movement component. And
有效的值给我们刚刚创建的指针。所以它将是自定义运动组件。而
here we need to do a cast. So the type is going to be you custom movement component. And I'm
这里我们需要做一个转换。所以类型将是你的自定义运动组件。而我要
going to cast from this character movement. So you can see this function, it returns a
我将从这个角色的运动中投出。所以你可以看到这个函数，它返回一个
pointer of type you character movement component. And this is how we can get hold of our custom
指针的类型是你的角色运动组件。这就是我们如何能够掌握我们的自定义
movement component. And there's one more thing that we need to do. So this variable here,
运动组件。还有一件事我们需要做。所以这个变量在这里、
this is a private variable. And later we'll need to access this variable inside of our
这是一个私有变量。以后我们将需要在我们的
nm instance class. So same as other components, I like to create a public getter for it. So
nm实例类中访问这个变量。所以和其他组件一样，我喜欢为它创建一个公共的getter。所以
I'm going to copy this type and I'm going to scroll down to this public section. And
我将复制这个类型，并向下滚动到这个公共部分。而且
same as these two public getters, it's going to be another force inline. And the type is
和这两个公共获取器一样，它将成为另一个内联的力量。这个类型是
going to be our custom movement component. I'm going to call this get custom movement
将是我们的自定义运动组件。我将把这个称为 "自定义运动"。
component. It's going to be a const and I'm going to return this custom movement component.
组件。它将是一个常量，我将返回这个自定义运动组件。
All right, that should be everything that we need to do from code. I'm going to press
好了，这应该是我们在代码中需要做的一切。我将按
control plus F5 to launch my editor. All right, go back to my project. Since we just changed
control加F5来启动我的编辑器。好了，回到我的项目中去。由于我们刚刚改变了
the default movement component for the character class, I like to create a new blueprint class
角色类的默认运动组件，我想为我们的角色创建一个新的蓝图类
for our character. So go back to my content folder, I'm going to create a new folder.
为我们的角色创建一个新的蓝图类。所以回到我的内容文件夹，我将创建一个新的文件夹。
I'm going to call this one ClimbSystem and go back to my C++ classes. Right mouse button
我将把这个文件夹称为ClimbSystem，然后回到我的C++类。鼠标右键
click this character class and select create blueprint class based on it. I'm going to
点击这个角色类，选择在其基础上创建蓝图类。我将
change this name to BP_climbingSystemCharacter and I'm going to place it under this folder
把这个名字改为BP_climbingSystemCharacter，并把它放在我们刚刚创建的这个文件夹下。
that we just created and click create blueprint class. And now you can see in here it's indeed
我们刚刚创建的这个文件夹下，然后点击创建蓝图类。现在你可以在这里看到，它确实是
using our custom movement component and this is our component class. Great, everything
使用我们的自定义运动组件，这就是我们的组件类。很好，一切
is working and now we just need to reassign the mesh. So I'm going to select this one
现在我们只需要重新分配网格。所以我将选择这个
and for this skeletal mesh, I'm going to change this to SKM_ManySimple and I'm going to move
对于这个骨架网格，我要把它改成SKM_ManySimple，然后我把它移到
it down a little bit to something like this and rotate it 90 degrees. And for this animation
我将把它往下移一点，就像这样，并将它旋转90度。而对于这个动画
mode, I'm going to change this anim class from none to ABPE_Many. We'll create our own
模式，我将把这个动画类别从无改为ABPE_Many。我们稍后将创建我们自己的
animation blueprint later. For now, the default animation blueprint comes with the project.
动画蓝图。现在，默认的动画蓝图是随项目提供的。
It's great for testing. And there's one more thing that we need to do. So if you click
它对测试很有帮助。还有一件事我们需要做。因此，如果你点击
this BP_climbingSystemCharacter, since we've just created a new character blueprint, we'll
这个BP_climbingSystemCharacter，由于我们刚刚创建了一个新的角色蓝图，我们需要重新分配所有这些输入。
need to reassign all those input actions and mapping context in order to have the input
我们需要重新分配所有这些输入动作和映射上下文，以便将输入的内容
back. So instead of the search bar, I'm going to search input and for this default mapping
回来。因此，我不使用搜索栏，而是使用搜索输入，并为这个默认的映射
context, I'm going to assign this IMC default. Jump action will be this jump action and move
上下文，我将分配这个IMC默认值。跳跃动作将是这个跳跃动作和移动
will be this IAMove and assign this look action also our climb action and click compile. And
将是这个IAMove，并指定这个外观动作和我们的爬升动作，然后点击编译。然后
in order to use our newly created character class, we'll need to create a new game mode.
为了使用我们新创建的角色类，我们需要创建一个新的游戏模式。
So right mouse button click and select blueprint class. I'm going to select this game mode
所以鼠标右键点击，选择蓝图类。我将选择这个游戏模式
base. I'm going to call this one BP_testGameMode and go inside of this word settings, change
基础。我将把这个游戏模式称为BP_testGameMode，并在这个词的内部进行设置，将游戏模式改为
the game mode to this BP_testGameMode and this default Pwn class, I'm going to change
将游戏模式改为BP_testGameMode，将这个默认的Pwn类改为
it to BP_climbingSystemCharacter. Alright, I'm going to click play and you can see we
改为BP_climbingSystemCharacter。好的，我将点击播放，你可以看到我们
are using this SKM_ManySimple and all the movement code is working as usual. That's
你可以看到我们正在使用这个SKM_ManySimple，所有的运动代码都在照常工作。这真是
great. Later, when you implement this by yourself, in order to override the default movement
很好。以后，当你自己实现这个时，为了覆盖默认的运动
component, there's something that we need to do through this object initializer and
组件，我们需要通过这个对象的初始化器来做一些事情。
after doing that, don't forget to create a new BP_character class. Otherwise, our custom
之后，别忘了创建一个新的BP_character类。否则，我们的自定义
movement component might not work properly and also don't forget to reassign all those
否则，我们的自定义运动组件可能无法正常工作，也别忘了重新分配所有这些
input actions. Alright, time for you to create your own custom movement component and I'll
输入动作。好了，是时候让你创建你自己的自定义运动组件了。
see you in the next lecture.
在下一个讲座中见。
[music]
[音乐]